Guide to the Rice University Wiess School of Natural Sciences dean search records, 1997-1998 UA 129
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Rice University Wiess School of Natural Sciences dean search records
1997-1998
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Rice University
UA 129
0.25 Linear Feet (1 box)
In 1997, Rice University began a national search for a new dean for the Wiess School of Natural Sciences. This collection contains records related to that search, including lists of committee members, lists of candidates, correspondence, university news releases and other related records, such as the 1997 strategic plan for the Wiess School of Natural Sciences.
Biographical / Historical
Wiess School of Natural Sciences was dedicated in 1979 to honor Harry C. Wiess and Olga K. Wiess. However, Rice has been dedicated to the natural sciences since its inception in 1912. The 2006-2007 General Announcements describe the Wiess School of Natural Sciences as being comprised of biochemistry and cell biology, chemistry, earth science, ecology and evolutionary biology, mathematics, and physics and astronomy.
Scope and Contents
In 1997, Rice University began a national search for a new dean for the Wiess School of Natural Sciences. This collection contains records related to that search, including lists of committee members, lists of candidates, correspondence, university news releases and other related records, such as the 1997 strategic plan for the Wiess School of Natural Sciences.
Access Restrictions
This material is restricted for privacy reasons. Contact the Woodson Research Center to learn more about the restrictions or about accessing the collection.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Accruals
The Woodson does not expect to acquire additional records for this collection.
Acquisition Information
Collection acquired from Rice University administration.
Index Terms
Subjects
Universities and colleges
Document Types
clippings (information artifacts); notes; letters (correspondence)
Subjects (Corporations)
Rice University. Wiess School of Natural Sciences
- Series I: Dean search records, 1997-1998; 143688
  - Announcement of Rice's new dean of engineering, 1988; 143696 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, October 1997-April 1998; 143695 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Description of Dean position, circa 1997; 143694 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Interview scripts, 1998; 143693 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Invitation for applications and nominations, 1997; 143692 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - List of candidate, 1997-1998; 143691 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Search committee, October 1997- February 1998; 143690 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Science (magazine) recruitment advertizing, circa September 30 1997; 143689 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Series II: Materials related to search, 1997-1998; 143684
  - News clips about Houston, 1998; 143687 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Strategic Plan for Wiess School of Natural Sciences, circa 1997; 143686 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - External Review Committee report from Institute for Advanced Study, March 10, 1998; 143685 (Box 2, Folder 11)